<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Words of a terrible kid</title>
    <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Words of a terrible kid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 01:08:30 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mangesh.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Flight</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/my-first-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 01:08:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/my-first-flight/</guid>
      <description>As always, it all starts with adventures and problems, and in a way that I can later laugh at. This was a similar way.&#xA;IndiaFOSS 3.0 IndiaFOSS 3.0 was around the corner and we all were preparing for the conference working hard day and night without sleep. That day all of a sudden from nowhere my friends told me that my class test was announced for 26-27-28 October and IndiaFOSS 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Parents Happy</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/making-parents-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 22:02:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/making-parents-happy/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost 4-5+ years since I started feeling negative about the Indian Education System and the structure the Indian govt has for engineering colleges to be specific.&#xA;I thought of starting to build a team for managing and organizing regular monthly meetups in my city as a continuation of SolapurFOSS. We wanted new volunteers because I and a couple of my classmates (4 of us) organized and tried running SolapurFOSS smoothly but now we&amp;rsquo;re on the verge of exiting the college as it&amp;rsquo;s our 3 year and the last semester.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Fix Without Even Breaking</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/trying-to-fix-without-even-breaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 15:07:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/trying-to-fix-without-even-breaking/</guid>
      <description>So, a few days ago (2 weeks probably) I noticed a lot of heat on the bottom side of my laptop only when I was plugged in. So, I started looking up solutions on the internet and installed auto-cpufreq and also started using thermald which I knew before too but had not installed on my Thinkpad t490. So, I did and casually I thought that I would also additionally install and configure thermald.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Own a Website</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/why-own-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 02:51:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/why-own-a-website/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is subject to errors (grammatical or more) as i&amp;rsquo;m writing this to give a try at writing something in one go and at 3:00 AM. Pardon any errors!&#xA;Back in 2020, when I had got started living more on the internet and with virtual friends. I always had a weird attraction towards cool, minimal and very worn out websites which were very old (I still like finding such websites).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Night With Tmp Files</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/christmas-night-with-tmp-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 01:36:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/christmas-night-with-tmp-files/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog that will help me always remember that checking the command twice before running is the best way to not lead towards any fuck ups on a Linux machine. and also to give me trauma even ahead in the future.&#xA;I noticed tmp files I was working on some things inside the terminal and I noticed that there are a lot of temporary files with names ~/.bash_history-some id.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 01:40:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Mangesh. I am a student, tinkerer and a geek pursuing a Diploma curse. I am a person of diverse interests and opinions. I am a Free Software enthusiast and one of the first Free Software I used in my initial days was Linux and have been using it since then as a daily driver.&#xA;This is my personal blog page, where I want to rant, present my opinions and write notes of whatever I want to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confused as a Student</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/confusion/</guid>
      <description>This blog is me ranting about why I am way too confused as a student.&#xA;What is the confusion about ? I am a Computer Engineering student pursuing my diploma in a private college in my city. Unlike the others, I am someone who questions every small thing a lot and at times I’m very rude to people of my age group near or around my college circle. I am barely accessible to everyone and do not have a big circle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living Alone</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/livingalone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/livingalone/</guid>
      <description>A random blog where I&amp;rsquo;m blabbering I recently moved to Bangalore, it&amp;rsquo;s called the IT/Technical Hub of India. Well, I moved here for my Internship at FOSS United. Thanks a lot to my managers they invited me to come and work from office. And for me this is kind of a very difference.&#xA;Before this I have never lived alone for more than 7 days, this is the first ever time when I&amp;rsquo;ll be leaving alone, 650 km away from my parents in a very new and busy city.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conquering Maharashtras Highest Peak</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/kalsubai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/kalsubai/</guid>
      <description>This is a blog which will let y&amp;rsquo;all readers know how I am feeling after climbing Maharashtra&amp;rsquo;s highest peak. Words probably won&amp;rsquo;t be of much help but let&amp;rsquo;s give it a try.&#xA;It all starts with a post So, there&amp;rsquo;s a local community of trekkers in my city called EcoFriendlyClub. They&amp;rsquo;ve been organizing treks to various places in the Sahyadri Mountain Ranges from the last 7-8 years. I&amp;rsquo;ve been them many times to various places.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surely you&#39;re Joking Mr.Feynman</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/sujmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/sujmf/</guid>
      <description>Book Review - Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking Mr. Feynman So, those of you who like reading, physics and crazy brains. You might have come across a famous, physicist and he is called ~Dick Feynman~ Richard Feynman. He was a physicist, a curious, a natural problem solver. This blog is all about one of his biographical books named &amp;ldquo;Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking Mr. Richard&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;How I came across the book? I am a curious guy and I came across Richard Feynman through one of my friends Github Readme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources I use</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/resources/</guid>
      <description>These are some of the blogs/articles and links to important resources which I refer to or love reading. This list will keep on updating in the future too!&#xA;Articles/Blogs How to Become a Hacker The Scene Linux users vs Linux Culture A start to programming About Atul Phrack Some good blogs from people rgz wother&amp;rsquo;s avatar git ti and tri Resources tldp Kernel Newbies: Soon when I get a long hooooliday will study this!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experience at PuneFOSS&#39;23</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/punefoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/punefoss/</guid>
      <description>How it started ? A few days ago, as you may know, I attended MumbaiFOSS. I actually booked tickets for both Mumbai and Pune FOSS events because the reason behind booking both was that whatever I learned from MumbaiFOSS, I could apply in PuneFOSS. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to just be an attendee at events. It felt weird to just go and listen, attend and get a couple of swags. I was already familiar with public speaking, as I had given introductory talks on Brain Chips in my class and in competitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MumbaiFOSS 23</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/mumbaifoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/mumbaifoss/</guid>
      <description>My journey to MumbaiFOSS and my experience there I&amp;rsquo;m doing my 2nd-year diploma in computer engineering. I have always been a huge fan of FOSS such as GNU/Linux, it was the reason I chose computer engineering but unfortunately, there was nothing in-depth on it in my course curriculum. I had seen people share posters of a FOSS event called IndiaFOSS on LinkedIn. I just looked up about it on the internet, it was conducted by FOSS United, a foundation that aims at promoting and strengthening the FOSS ecosystem in India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Blog about BCI</title>
      <link>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/bci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mangesh.xyz/posts/bci/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A brain chip is a very tiny computer chip that is similar to a size of a coin. Our brain pretty much works similarly to a computer i/o process. There are 86 Billion neurons in your brain.&#xA;Bio-MEHHHH Neurons are responsible for sending or receiving information. A neuron is divided into three sub-parts: A dendrite responsible for receiving a signal, a cell body that processes the signal, and an axon that sends a signal out.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
